<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[my egoistic]]></title>
  <link href="http://sway.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://sway.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2011-12-30T14:50:14+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://sway.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[honza]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[honza@egoistic.biz]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Transition]]></title>
    <link href="http://sway.github.com/blog/2011/12/23/transition/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-23T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://sway.github.com/blog/2011/12/23/transition</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Four months ago I was sweating my ass off waiting for the delayed flight to Seoul. At that time, I had no idea whats gonna happen during the next four months. I was nervous and excited at the same time, but I was really looking forward to it, whatever the &#8220;it&#8221; meant at that time.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>And now it&#8217;s done…this was probably the best semester of my life, and I doubt that something could possibly top that, since next semester will be all about my master thesis, which does not sound exciting at all.</p>

<p>The last few weeks at KAIST were quite hectic. I was so &#8220;smart&#8221; that I left all my assignments for the last 10 days, so instead of having fun, chilling and trying to squeeze this &#8220;adventure&#8221; to maximum, I was squeezing my brain to produce two reports and a presentation, while preparing for three exams. I handed in the last report on Thursday at 3:30am, 16.5 hours before leaving KAIST. On Thursday I just managed to finish packing, get an ice cream with Kate (which I promised a long time ago), eat one last combination pizza at Pizza School and say bye to the girls from the International office. It was a sad goodbye to be honest. After that Marc, Mario and me took a taxi to Seoul Station and then the Airport Express to Incheon. Quick stop at the Duty-Free store (12yr old Balvenie) and off we go, 9.5 hours to Dubai.</p>

<p>But let&#8217;s rewind a bit. My first exam was on Wednesday, the 14th. It was the Korean language exam, and since I am quite comfortable with my Korean knowledge, I did not have any big problems with it. A+, click! (I hope)</p>

<p>The other two exams were more difficult, though. The courses were <em>Value Innovation with IT</em> and <em>Overview of Internet Technologies</em>, and the exams were on Monday and Tuesday, respectively. Even though I basically spent the weekend studying, due to my lack of motivation and low morale I was not really confident about result. The Monday exam was quite difficult, and from time to time I had to resort to more less bullshitting tactics and using phrases such as <em>streamlining internal processes</em> and <em>increasing synergy</em>. I know, crappy buzzwords connected into meaningless phrases, but don&#8217;t judge me, I really tried!</p>

<p>The second exam, for which I prepared on Monday afternoon, was much easier. The whole course was a piece of cake for me, since the topic were Internet technologies, networking, TCP/IP and so on. Since I already had a course like that during my bachelor (much more detailed and technical, of course), it was no problem for me, as opposed to my classmates, that had no technical background or previous knowledge. Given the fact that the professor sometimes went into too much technical detail, most of the class was quite lost. I am really curious about the overall results, because the exam was quite difficult as well, and I think it even covered topics not mentioned in the slides.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I'm the IT guy]]></title>
    <link href="http://sway.github.com/blog/2010/01/21/im-the-IT-guy/"/>
    <updated>2010-01-21T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://sway.github.com/blog/2010/01/21/im-the-IT-guy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>&#8220;You are studying at FEL? Then you are good at computers, right?&#8221;</p>

<p>&#8220;Well, yeah&#8221;</p>

<p>&#8220;Cool, could you fix my computer? My minesweeper/freecell/internet/game/whatever is not working&#8221;</p></blockquote>

<p>This is a conversation everyone that studies software engineering or other flavor of computer science receives at least once. For most people, computer science == &#8220;I fix computers&#8221;. <em>It&#8217;s not true!</em> Having CS background, I consider myself to be a little geeky. I had switched to Linux (Fedora 3) from Windows 2000 in 2004, and been using it until I bought my MacBook Pro in 2010. I love terminal, bash, AppleScript and task automation in general. I use LaTeX for almost everything, even for shopping lists. I&#8217;d rather spend 2 hours figuring something out than doing it other way. And yeah, I lauch at IT jokes. Like this one:</p>

<blockquote><p>Our company is having a fancy dress party. Ah, there comes our CEO, in the mask of Zorro. There is the beautiful girl from accounting dressed as a nun and there comes our network administrator, wearing the 255.255.255.0 mask.</p></blockquote>

<p>Funny, right:) Anyway, the true power of geeks is in most cases really appreciated when someone needs to fix something. During my stay here in Delft, I already had two opportunities to prove my &#8220;IT status&#8221;</p>

<h4>Situation 1: DHCP server trouble</h4>

<p>Our dorms are on a FTTD (fibre-to-the-dorms) network. For each &#8220;segment&#8221;, there is a HP ProCurve switch, which is then connected to central DNS + DHCP + PPPoE server. The PPPoE is autenticated agains university&#8217;s RADIUS servers, but that is not that relevant.</p>

<p>Imagine this situation. One morning, I wake up, get my coffee, wake my MBP up and try to open the news. But it does not work, and, what more, the PPPoE tunnel is not &#8220;established&#8221;. Regular, non-IT poisoned person would try restarting their computer, but that won&#8217;t help at all. I did not. Instead, I checked the network settings, and I found out that I got my IP from some random DHCP server &#8212; it was from 192.168.0.0/24 network, which is far from the right one. I&#8217;ve remembered, that <a href="http://swarm.cz">diagon_swarm</a> had a similar problem. This happens when there is some stupid person, that wants to have Wi-Fi in his room, so he buys a router and plugs it in instead of his computer. Unfortunately, he uses the wrong port, so instead of using WAN, he plugs it in one of the LAN ports. That means, that when my laptop sent DHCPDISCOVER packet, the DHCP server in the router got it first, and quickly responded, giving me a wrong IP.</p>

<p>How to fix that? It was quite easy &#8212; my stream of consciousness was like this: &#8220;He is stupid, so he probably has his default password on the router&#8221;. And indeed, after typing in the gateway address, I was able to log in with obvious admin:admin combination. Turning off the DHCP was a matter of few clicks, and I even resisted the temptation to change his master password. I&#8217;m such a nice guy.</p>

<p>Well, my internet connection was running smoothly again, and it has been since then. I bet that guy does not even know he had the DHCP server turned on.</p>

<h4>Situation 2: DNS fucked up</h4>

<p>This has happened yesterday. In the evening,</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My new home!]]></title>
    <link href="http://sway.github.com/blog/2010/01/14/my-new-home/"/>
    <updated>2010-01-14T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://sway.github.com/blog/2010/01/14/my-new-home</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is my new home. The virtual one, of course. It is no longer hosted on a standalone hosting, but I have decided to fully outsource all the service I use
under my domain. It&#8217;s cheaper (as in free) and it fulfills all my needs.</p>

<ol>
<li>Sometimes I used my hosting to store temporary rubbish (screenshots etc.), but now we have cloud storage, there is no need for that. Now I use mainly
<a href="http://dropbox.com/">Dropbox</a> (as for collaboration) or <a href="http://cloud.ly">cloud.app</a> for temporary stuff.</li>
<li>E-mail and calendar is handled by Google Apps/iCloud (still have to decide which one to use based on my next phone). And that&#8217;s all&#8230;</li>
<li>For blogging (or &#8220;blogging&#8221; in my case), I have used Posterous anyway. Now the site is stored on <a href="http://github.com">GitHub</a>, I can use jekyll, which is a static content generator, with Markdown and Liquid static support.</li>
</ol>


<p>All these services offer free versions, that are sufficient for my needs. When I realize, that two years ago I was thinking about getting a HostMonster
account, it is a kind of a scaledown. But well, as we grow older, we need less stuff.</p>

<p>Anyhow, I will try to keep it running here. I know my blogs usually die after few months, but let&#8217;s give this one a chance.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
