<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Stuff | my egoistic]]></title>
  <link href="http://sway.github.com/blog/categories/stuff/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://sway.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-01-24T20:59:36+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://sway.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[honza]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[honza@egoistic.biz]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A fresh start]]></title>
    <link href="http://sway.github.com/blog/2012/01/01/a-fresh-start/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-01T15:46:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://sway.github.com/blog/2012/01/01/a-fresh-start</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Farewell to 2011, welcome to 2012. One of the greatest years of my life has ended, so it&rsquo;s time to clear the backlog and start again.</p>

<p>The last two weeks in Korea were quite demanding. I was so smart to leave all the stuff from the second quarter for the last moment, so I had to deal with three exams, two reports and a presentation in the last 10 days. No fun.</p>

<p>Apart from school, however, it was quite nice. We had a closing dinner and party night with fellow exchange students, went for a dinner with Jin and Kayla, me and Marc did some souvenir shopping, I finally went for the ice cream with Kate, sent a package back home (well, to Holland) and managed to stuff all my stuff into the suitcase (26kg).</p>

<!--more-->

<p>The flight home was long and boring, except for one nice moment when I met one of the Czech girls from KDI in Dubai (she had seat 30G) and one friend of a friend coming from Angola (31F). And yes, I had 31G. So, on a Friday afternoon, after spending the last 27 hours on the way, crossing 8 timezones, eating 4 airplane meals, and watching 2 movies<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup>, our Airbus A330-200 landed in Prague and I was back home.</p>

<p>This blog is something like my zillionth attempt to write a one, because I am not very good at keeping a regularly updated blog running. However, because I managed to regularly update <a href="http://soulexchange.wordpress.com">Seoul Exchange</a>, the blog about my Korean adventures, I decided to give it a shot with my regular life as well. So, stay tuned!</p>

<p>Btw. I will move the posts from there here as well, but it will take some time since the WordPress markup is somehow f-ed up and difficult to convert automagically.</p>

<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
      <p>Everything Must Go and Transformers 3. Seriously, the chick in T3 is kind of weird.<a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
