<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Stuff | my egoistic]]></title>
  <link href="http://sway.github.com/blog/categories/stuff/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://sway.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-01-01T19:40:01+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://sway.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[honza]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[honza@egoistic.biz]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A fresh start]]></title>
    <link href="http://sway.github.com/blog/2012/01/01/a-fresh-start/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-01T15:46:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://sway.github.com/blog/2012/01/01/a-fresh-start</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Farewell to 2011, welcome to 2012. One of the greatest years of my life has ended, so it's time to clear the backlog and start again.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>The last two weeks in Korea were quite demanding. I was so smart to leave all the stuff from the second quarter for the last moment, so I had to deal with three exams, two reports and a presentation in the last 10 days. No fun.</p>

<p>Fortunately, everything worked out well, and even though I don't know my grades yet, I hope it's gonna be OK…</p>

<p>Apart from school stuff, the last few days in Seoul were lovely. On Tuesday we had the last group dinner (bulgogi and lots of soju) and then went to Hongdae for the last time. On Wednesday, apart from being hungover and finishing one report, we went for a dinner with the girls from the International Office, and even though we originally planned to get something near the campus, we ended up going to Apujeong to a nice thai place. After coming home at 12:30am I finished my KBC report and went to to print it out and hand it in. Seriously, going to the lab at 3am felt so Korean. Eventually, I got to bed at 5:30-ish after packing my suitcase and saying goodbye to André and Karin that left the dorm at 4:30.</p>

<p>On Thursday I went for an ice cream with Kate, finished packing and waited for 7:30pm to leave the dorm, head to the international office to check out and then take a taxi and the train to Incheon. Saying goodbye to the girls in the international office was sad, because they were really awesome to us during the 4 months.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Transition]]></title>
    <link href="http://sway.github.com/blog/2011/12/23/transition/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-23T16:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://sway.github.com/blog/2011/12/23/transition</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Four months ago I was sweating my ass off waiting for the delayed flight to Seoul. At that time, I had no idea whats gonna happen during the next four months. I was nervous and excited at the same time, but I was really looking forward to it, whatever the "it" meant at that time.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>And now it's done…this was probably the best semester of my life, and I doubt that something could possibly top that, since next semester will be all about my master thesis, which does not sound exciting at all.</p>

<p>The last few weeks at KAIST were quite hectic. I was so "smart" that I left all my assignments for the last 10 days, so instead of having fun, chilling and trying to squeeze this "adventure" to maximum, I was squeezing my brain to produce two reports and a presentation, while preparing for three exams. I handed in the last report on Thursday at 3:30am, 16.5 hours before leaving KAIST. On Thursday I just managed to finish packing, get an ice cream with Kate (which I promised a long time ago), eat one last combination pizza at Pizza School and say bye to the girls from the International office. It was a sad goodbye to be honest. After that Marc, Mario and me took a taxi to Seoul Station and then the Airport Express to Incheon. Quick stop at the Duty-Free store (12yr old Balvenie) and off we go, 9.5 hours to Dubai.</p>

<p>But let's rewind a bit. My first exam was on Wednesday, the 14th. It was the Korean language exam, and since I am quite comfortable with my Korean knowledge, I did not have any big problems with it. A+, click! (I hope)</p>

<p>The other two exams were more difficult, though. The courses were <em>Value Innovation with IT</em> and <em>Overview of Internet Technologies</em>, and the exams were on Monday and Tuesday, respectively. Even though I basically spent the weekend studying, due to my lack of motivation and low morale I was not really confident about result. The Monday exam was quite difficult, and from time to time I had to resort to more less bullshitting tactics and using phrases such as <em>streamlining internal processes</em> and <em>increasing synergy</em>. I know, crappy buzzwords connected into meaningless phrases, but don't judge me, I really tried!</p>

<p>The second exam, for which I prepared on Monday afternoon, was much easier. The whole course was a piece of cake for me, since the topic were Internet technologies, networking, TCP/IP and so on. Since I already had a course like that during my bachelor (much more detailed and technical, of course), it was no problem for me, as opposed to my classmates, that had no technical background or previous knowledge. Given the fact that the professor sometimes went into too much technical detail, most of the class was quite lost. I am really curious about the overall results, because the exam was quite difficult as well, and I think it even covered topics not mentioned in the slides.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
